Guide to the Robert Grady Dawson Papers, 1906-1994
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Robert Grady Dawson papers 1906-1994
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Dawson, Robert Grady.
9.4 Linear Feet 3647 Items
Duke University graduate and Methodist clergyman in N.C.
Collection consists chiefly of papers documenting Dawson's studies at Duke University's Divinity School, and his professional life as a minister in the Methodist Church. Included are subject files; many sermon texts; correspondence; family history; appointment books; an account book; papers written by Dawson as a student in the Duke University Divinity School, including a B.D. thesis; and an ordination certificate. There is one file folder of legal papers and photographs documenting the Howland-Dawson Gardens Endowment for the Sarah P. Duke Gardens.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Robert Grady Dawson Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift. Initial gift date unknown, addition in 2013.
Collection Overview
The Robert Grady Dawson Papers span the years 1906-1994, and consist chiefly of papers documenting Dawson's studies at Duke University's Divinity School, where he graduated in 1930, and his professional life thereafter as a minister in the Methodist Church. Included are alphabetically arranged subject files; many folders of sermon texts; correspondence; family history; appointment books; an account book; papers written by Dawson as a student in the Duke University Divinity School, including a B.D. thesis; and an ordination certificate. There is one file folder of legal papers and photographs documenting the Howland-Dawson Gardens Endowment for the Sarah P. Duke Gardens.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Church records and registers -- North Carolina
Clergy -- North Carolina -- Correspondence
Dawson family
Dawson, Robert Grady
Duke University -- Divinity School -- Students
Methodist Church -- Clergy -- Correspondence
Methodist Church -- North Carolina -- History
Sarah P. Duke Gardens
Sermons, American -- 20th century
Contents of Collection
- Robert Grady Dawson Papers, 1906-1994, (20 boxes)
  - Subject files, A-Da (Includes correspondence and Dawson biographical materials) (Box 1)
  - Subject files, De-Ga (Box 2)
  - Subject files, Gr-Pr (Box 3)
  - Subject files, Pr-St (Includes Dawson's service record) (Box 4)
  - Subject files, Te-Wo (Box 5)
  - Photographs (one folder)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 6)
  - Sermons (no order, listed by title on folder)
  - Sermons (Box 7)
  - Sermons (Box 8)
  - Sermons (Box 9)
  - Sermons (Box 10)
  - Sermons (Box 11)
  - Sermons (Box 12)
  - Sermons (Box 13)
  - Sermons (Box 14)
  - Sermons (Box 15)
  - Sermons (Box 16)
  - Memorial service booklet for Grady's wife, Elizabeth Howland Dawson, 1980 (includes biographical sketch)
  - Obituary for R. Grady Dawson, 1982
  - Sermon materials
  - Sermons and prayers
  - Sermons for youth
  - Sermons (Box 17)
  - Ministers' Wives Luncheons Programs
  - Biographical materials (R. Grady Dawson) (Box 18)
  - Thesis: Evidences of Immortality, 1930
  - Pocket appointment books ("Pastor's Books"), 1926-1948
  - Pocket appointment books ("Pastor's Books"), 1948-1962 (Box 19)
  - Pocket calendars (personal), 1958-1963, 1966-1974
  - Printed materials: Brochures, publicity (Box 20)
  - Thesis (duplicate, bound), 1930
  - Student notes (one binder)
  - Endowment for Sarah P. Duke Gardens, 1965-1994 (Box 21)
  - Cash book, New Bern District, 1962-1968 (Oversize-box 18)
  - Ordination papers
  - Diplomas
  - Other certificate (fraternity)